(
"ai_sub_version": "2.5.0",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 2,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 12,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"web_search_tool": "duckduckgo",
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": "libx264"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
冥界Halloween Night! FBKINGDOM
Underworld Halloween Night! FBKINGDOM
始まりはきっと 一つの願い
It all started with a single wish, I'm sure
それを抱いて 私たちは生まれた
Holding onto that, we were born
孤独な夜空 震える指で
In the lonely night sky, with trembling fingers...
点と点を繋げよう
let's connect the dots together.
1次元では 寂しすぎるから
Because one dimension is just too lonely...
私たちは 広がりを求めた
we sought out more space to grow.
点は線となり 線は立体となり
Points became lines, and lines became solids...
そこに距離が生まれたけれど
and though distance was born there...
3次元では ちょっと遠すぎるから
because three dimensions are a bit too far apart...
私たちは 平面に求めた
we sought for it on a flat plane.
点は線となり 線は星座となり
Points became lines, and lines became constellations...
この夜空を繋ぐよ
connecting this night sky.
自分らしく いられる場所を
For a place where I could truly be myself...
気づけばずっと 探していた
I realized I'd been searching all along.
煌めく星よ この地に集え
O sparkling stars, gather here on this earth...
この旗を目印に
using this flag as your guide.
あの日君が いつもそこにいたから
Because you were always there back then...
嬉しくて続けられたんだ今日まで
I was so happy I could keep going until today.
忘れないでね 僕らの星座は
Please don't forget, our constellation...
君がいたから生まれた
was born because you were here.
たとえ君が いつも時を生きても
Even if you live through all of time...
何かを好きになる気持ち大切に
please treasure that feeling of loving something.
歌い続けてね 僕らの星座は
Keep on singing, for our constellation...
君がいるから生まれた
was born because you are here.
夜空に輝き
It shines in the night sky...
明日へと繋がる
and connects us to tomorrow.
未来を
To the future...
目指すよ
we'll aim.
共に
Together...
歩もう
let's walk.
これは僕らのキセキ。
This is our miracle.
僕とキミと、大切なあの子の
Of me, of you, and of that precious person...
この王国で過ごす、かけがえのない日々を綴る
chronicling the irreplaceable days spent in this kingdom...
僕たちの物語。
this is our story.
小説「FBKINGDOM STORY」ED主題歌抜粋
Excerpt from the Novel "FBKINGDOM STORY" Ending Theme
僕の居る意味はどこにあるの？
Where can I find the meaning of my existence?
誰かに必要とされたかった
I wanted to be needed by someone.
夢や希望も捨てきれないけど
I can't completely throw away my dreams and hopes...
なんとなく今を生きている
yet I am just living my life day by day.
どれだけ叫んでも
No matter how much I scream...
この声は君には届かない
this voice won't reach you.
どれだけ叫んでも
No matter how much I scream...
この声は君には届かない
this voice won't reach you.
金木犀の匂いがした
I catch the scent of osmanthus.
明日のことも忘れたくなった
I wanted to forget all about tomorrow.
いっそ逃げてしまおうかな
I wonder if I should just run away...
僕は悲劇の主人公だ
I am the protagonist of this tragedy.
やさしいヒトで居たいな
I want to stay as a kind person...
でもそんな思いも偽善だ
but even that thought is hypocritical.
誰も幸せにできないの
I can't make anyone happy.
都合良いね、涙が出るの
It's convenient, isn't it? Tears come out.
Convenient, isn't it? Tears are falling
ああ　どれだけ歌っても
Ah, no matter how much I sing
この声は君には届かない
This voice will never reach you
ああ　どれだけ歌っても
Ah, no matter how much I sing
この声は君には届かない
This voice will never reach you
ああ　息が苦しくなる
Ah, it's getting hard to breathe
この歌もいつしか終わりが来る
This song too will eventually end
ああ　息が苦しくなる
Ah, it's getting hard to breathe
この地球もいつかは終わりが来る
This world too will one day end
金木犀の匂いをまた
Once again, the scent of fragrant olive...
思い出した
...reminded me
気付けば　駆けだしていた
By the time I noticed, I was running
揺れ動く　心のままに
Following my swaying heart
遠ざかる　白い壁
The white wall receding further away
一度も　振り返らずに
Without looking back even once
《生命》が　消え逝く季節の
In the season where life fades away
胸を刺す　気配の中で
Amidst the air that stabs at my chest
迫りくる　暗闇
The encroaching darkness
二度と　明けないような気がして
Feeling as if dawn would never come again
転がり落つそな心
A heart that feels like it's falling
必死に抱き止めていた
I was desperately holding on to it
星空へと続く長い坂道は
The long path leading to the starry sky
永遠にも　思えたから
Seemed like it could last forever
咲花や　散りぬるを
Like blooming flowers that eventually scatter
神代の《時代》より繰り返す
Repeating since the era of the gods
私はそれを　美しいとは
I have never, ever thought...
思ったことがない
...that such a thing was beautiful
久方の　春の陽を
The long-awaited spring sunlight
仮初めの影が奪い合う
Fought over by fleeting shadows
その営みを　美しいとは
I have never, ever thought...
思ったことがない
...that such a cycle was beautiful
諦めながら　生きてた
I lived my life while giving up
何も望まないように　それでも
Wishing for nothing, yet even so
手放せなかった
I couldn't let it go
最後の願いを　握りしめて
Clutching my final wish
駆け上がる
I run up the hill
尾丸ポルカ
Omaru Polka
猫又おかゆ
Nekomata Okayu
大神ミオ
Ookami Mio
天音かなた
Amane Kanata
さくらみこ
Sakura Miko
鷹嶺ルイ
Takane Lui
フワワ・アビスガード　モココ・アビスガード
Fuwawa Abyssgard & Mococo Abyssgard
白上フブキ
Shirakami Fubuki
我武者羅に生きるお前が笑われて
You, living recklessly, were mocked
楽に生きる奴らが徳をする世界で
In a world where those who live easy prosper
我だけはお前のことを笑わない
I alone will not laugh at you
皆が指差し笑おうとも我は笑わない
Even if everyone points and laughs, I will not laugh
ああ人は滅んでゆく　綻んでゆく
Ah, people perish, they fall apart
才を妬み合い富を奪い合い
Envying talents and stealing wealth
ああ人は滅んでゆく　綻んでゆく
Ah, people perish, they fall apart
その果てに見えた海は
The sea I saw at the end of it all...
地獄だろうか？それとも地獄だろうか？
...is it hell? Or is it hell?
我武者羅に生きるお前が笑われて
You, living recklessly, were mocked
楽に生きる奴らが徳をする世界で
In a world where those who live easy prosper
我だけはお前のことを笑わない
I alone will not laugh at you
皆が指差し笑おうとも我は笑わない！
Even if everyone points and laughs, I won't laugh!
正直に生きるお前が貶されて
You who live honestly are disparaged
嘘で生きる奴らが徳となる世界で
In a world where those who live by lies are rewarded
我だけはお前の腕を離さない！
I alone will not let go of your arm!
時を刻み忘れようとも我は離さない！
Even if we forget to keep time, I won't let go!
我は忘れない！
I won't forget!
身を粉にして働いても
Even if I work myself to the bone
感謝されないことも……（シパシパ）
There are times I'm not thanked... (Shiba-shiba)
「自己犠牲」を受け入れも
Even if I accept "self-sacrifice"
限界がもうやってくるから
Because my limit is already approaching
自分を大事に愛せばいい
You just need to love and value yourself
それは他人を愛すること
That is what it means to love others
ああ人は溢れてゆく 淀んでゆく
Ah, people overflow, becoming stagnant
元に戻ってゆく
Returning to how they were
ああ人は泳いでゆく 救われてゆく
Ah, people swim through, being saved
君に逢えたから……
Because I was able to meet you...
君を愛したから……
Because I loved you...
君が戦うなら……
If you are going to fight...
僕も戦うから！
Then I will fight too!
我武者羅に生きるお前が笑われて
You who live recklessly are laughed at
楽に生きる奴らが徳をする世界で
In a world where those who live easily benefit
我だけはお前のことを笑わない！
I alone will not laugh at you!
皆が指差し笑おうとも我は笑わない！
Even if everyone points and laughs, I won't laugh!
正直に生きるお前が貶されて
You who live honestly are disparaged
嘘で生きる奴らが徳となる世界で
In a world where those who live by lies are rewarded
我だけはお前の腕を離さない！
I alone will not let go of your arm!
時を刻み忘れようとも我は離さない！
Even if we forget to keep time, I won't let go!
我は離さない！
I won't let go!
我は忘れない！
I won't forget!
それんじゃ今夜は、この王国のお話をしていこう。
Well then, tonight, let's talk about this kingdom.
嘘か真か、
Whether it's a lie or the truth,
ここに記されている本は内容がコロコロと変わってしまう、不思議な本でね。
the contents of the book recorded here change all the time; it's a mysterious book, you see.
さて、今回はどんなお話になっているかな。
Now, I wonder what kind of story it's become this time.
これはあるサーカスの一団が王国へ訪れ、
This is a story of a certain circus troupe visiting a kingdom,
まだ未熟な座長さんが綺羅びやかなステージに包まれたお話。
and a story of a still inexperienced ringmaster being embraced by a glittering stage.
ああ…これが私が望んだ夢のエンディング！
Ah... this is the dream ending I desired!
さあ、今日も始まりました～！
Now, it's starting today too~!
煌びやか、享楽のパレード
A glittering, hedonistic parade
常識もここでは無関係
Common sense is irrelevant here
踊れ歌え騒げ全て忘れて
Dance, sing, make a racket, and forget everything
細かいことは置いといて
Leave the small details aside
とりあえず身を任せてみな
For now, just try surrendering yourself
幸福を少し分けるような饗宴
A banquet that seems to share a bit of happiness
Show Time!
積もりゆく不安や後悔
Accumulating anxiety and regret
今だけはちょっと目を背けて
Just for now, look away a little
そのままじゃ楽しめないじゃん この場だけは何もかも忘れて
You can't enjoy it like that, can you? Just here, forget everything
幾千の価値観全部 引っ括め楽しませたげる！
I'll bundle up all the thousands of values and make you have fun!
百鬼夜行もビックリの 隊を成している
Forming a procession that would even surprise a night parade of 100 demons
怪奇模した戯劇が幕開け
The opening of a comedy imitating the bizarre
一目見ればたちまち虜に！？
If you take one look, you'll instantly be captivated!?
どんな愛も受け入れてくれる
It accepts any kind of love
ここだけはあなたの理想郷
This place alone is your utopia
「もう間もなく主役の登場、一時でも目を離さないで！」
“Very soon, the star appears—don't look away for even a moment!”
眩いほどのステージが始まる。
The dazzling stage begins.
華々しいスポットライトの中
In the middle of the magnificent spotlight
目を奪うような妙技の数々
Numerous eye-catching feats
この空間が世界で一番 “娯楽”の名に相応しいんだ！
This space is the most worthy in the world of the name "entertainment"!
割れんばかりの歓声と拍手で ショーは終わっていく
With thunderous cheers and applause, the show comes to an end
↑まあ、これはあくまで理想の話なんですが^^;
↑Well, this is just an ideal story, though... ^^;
さて、今日も始めましょうか…
Now, shall we begin today as well...
あ～！ またやっちゃった～！
Ah! I did it again!
実際はご覧の通り まだまだ未熟な見習いなんです
In reality, as you can see, I'm still just an inexperienced apprentice
先人に憧れ持って 私も！と飛び込んだものの
Admiring my predecessors, I dove right in, saying 'Me too!'
現実はそんな簡単に 上手くいかないなあ…
But reality doesn't go that smoothly...
もういっかい！ 「怪奇模した喜劇が幕開け 一目見ればたちまち虜に！？」
One more time! 'A comedy mimicking the bizarre begins, and one look will make you a captive!?'
え？ 既にそれさっき見たなら なら、飽き性なあなたにも【朗報】
Eh? If you've already seen that just now, then, [Good News] for you who get bored easily
Q. ちょっと前の模倣をするだけ
Q. Just mimicking what happened a bit ago
A. 繰り返しじゃつまらない！ だから、ここから先は趣向を変えてみよう！
A. Repetition is boring! So, from here on, let's change things up!
ドタバタなサーカスの行方は 誰にも自分すらも分からない！？
The outcome of this slapstick circus, nobody knows, not even me!?
私を選んだ君だけでも楽しんでってよ～～～！！！ 損させないから
At least you, who chose me, please enjoy yourself!!! I won't let you down
いつの日か皆と楽しめる ショーがしたいんだよな～！
I want to put on a show one day that everyone can enjoy!
だからこそ、こんなとこで 挫けるわけとかないな～い！
That's exactly why there's no way I'm giving up here!
言葉なんかじゃ言い表せない あの感動を私もいつか…
I can't put it into words, that inspiration... I hope to one day...
とても偉大なこのステージに 見合っているか分かんないけれど
I don't know if I'm worthy of this great stage, but
観客全て、私の色で 染め尽くしてやろう！
I'll dye every single audience member in my own colors!
手始めに、今、眼の前の君たちからいくよ～～～！！！
To start off, I'm coming for you guys right in front of me now!!!
創造しよう 華々しいスポットライトの中 目を奪うような妙技の数々
Let's create, amidst the glorious spotlight, many eye-catching feats
この空間が世界で一番 “享楽”の名に相応しいんだ！
This space is the most fitting in the world for the name 'Pleasure'!
割れんばかりの歓声と拍手で ショーが終わっていく
With thunderous cheers and applause, the show comes to an end
ああ…これが私が望んだ夢のエンディング。
Ah... this is the dream ending I wished for.
これは花の国のお姫様がこの王国へいらっしゃった時のお話
This is a story about when the princess of the flower country came to this kingdom.
まだみんな彼女の事を知らない頃だったので
It was back when nobody knew about her yet,
国民の大半は、アホの子なんて言ってたけど、
so most of the citizens called her an airhead, but...
とっても心優しくそして気さくで頼りになるお姫様だったんだよ
She was a very kind-hearted, friendly, and reliable princess.
なんてったって、みこはお姫様なんだから！
After all, Miko is a princess!
女神！
Goddess!
聖女！
Saint!
叡智！
Wisdom!
聡明！
Brightness!
慈愛！
Benevolence!
博愛！
Philanthropy!
ですわ！
Indeed!
あたし なんてったってお姫様
I'm a princess after all
この人生におけるヒロイン
The heroine of this life
ですわー！
Indeed!
一生 姫プでイージーモード！
Princess-carry easy mode for life!
って思ったら勝手にどうぞ？
If that's what you think, go right ahead?
世間はいつも気まぐれ次第
The world is always at its own whims
有象無象ばかりでホント 人間不信になっちゃう！
Full of the common rabble, honestly, I'm losing faith in humanity!
気づいたのこの世界に 血も涙もないことを
I realized that in this world, there's neither blood nor tears
あれもダメ、これもダメ、それもダメ、 どれもダメ、現実は世知辛い！
That's no good, this is no good, that too, none of it, reality is harsh!
改変だ…
It's a reform...
全部改変ですわ…！
It's a total reform...!
あたし なんてったってお姫様
I'm a princess after all
この人生におけるヒロイン
The heroine of this life
悲しいシナリオも全部全部書き換えちゃうの
Even sad scenarios, I'll rewrite them all
だってだって お姫様
Because, after all, I'm a princess
自分の物語くらいは
At the very least, my own story...
キラキラ楽しまなきゃ ですわ！ですわ！ですわ！ですわ！
I have to enjoy it sparklingly! Indeed! Indeed! Indeed! Indeed!
今にみてなさい！
Just you watch!
運命なんて 改変して差し上げますわ！
Destiny? I'll reform it for you!
だれ？ だれ？ だれ？ だれ？
Who? Who? Who? Who?
裏で糸を引いてるのはだれ？
Who is pulling the strings behind the scenes?
操り人形だなんて
Being a puppet...
ごめんだわ まったく
I'm quite done with that
上品な顔してても
Even with an elegant face,
黒幕はあの人かも
That person might be the mastermind
まずはあたしが 強くならなきゃ
First, I have to become stronger
未来は変わらない
Future won't change
改革だ…
It's a revolution...
自分改革ですわ…！
It's a self-revolution...!
そうよ なんてったってお姫様
That's right, I'm a princess after all
あたしこそ最高権力者
I am the supreme ruler
生涯のすべての主導権はこちらにあるわ
The initiative for all of my life lies here
だってだって お姫様
Because, after all, I'm a princess
自分で決めたことくらいは
At least the things I decided for myself...
暗澹たるストーリーライン
A bleak storyline,
難攻不落と化しちゃえ
becoming an impregnable fortress.
アクロイドとされた探偵が
The detective who was made out as Ackroyd...
また一人姿を消したと言う
is said to have vanished once again.
綾なす辻のアリスがわ
Alice in the weaving crossroads,
横溝正史は江戸川か
Is Seishi Yokomizo or Edogawa next?
神田最弱探偵さん
The weakest detective of Kanda,
こんなんどう居ると思う？
how do you think they'll fare?
南無阿弥陀仏 ステップ
Namu Amida Butsu Step,
脳髄是れ密室なりや
Is the brain itself a locked room?
偶然会った人
The person met by chance,
偶然別れましょう
let us part by chance.
謎解きはこれから
The mystery-solving starts now.
「犯人はあなたですわ」
"The culprit is you!"
連続 密室 発火トリック 殺人事件
Serial, locked-room, fire-trick murder case.
推理作家の先生さん
The mystery writer, Sensei-san.
あははは！
Ahahaha!
うだるパズル うだるパズル いまだに出逢えず
Boiling puzzles, boiling puzzles, yet to meet...
ああもう、頭がこんがらがってきたけれど
Ah geez, my head is getting all tangled up, but...
ドトハライ・ドットコム あちゃちゃちゃパリパリ
Dotobarai dot com, achachacha pari-pari,
エブリバディわんこそば
Everybody, Wanko Soba.
「謎はおやつに入りません」
"Mysteries aren't included as snacks."
ドトハライ・ドットコム あちゃちゃちゃドンシャリ
Dotobarai dot com, achachacha don-shari,
エブリバディあばいばい
Everybody, bye-bye,
ない、ない、ない
nothing, nothing, nothing.
エキセントリック大変馬鹿げた末路に
To an eccentric, greatly foolish end,
万歳三唱 続いてご清聴
three cheers, and thanks for listening.
オリエント急行客車の窓
The window of the Orient Express,
あの怪盗たちが笑うと言う
it's said those phantom thieves are laughing.
黄昏に二人海原
Two people in the twilight ocean,
坂口安吾 無視したろ
Ango Sakaguchi, you ignored it, right?
ABCだかエビスだか
ABC or Ebisu or whatever,
レモンドちゃんとしてして
Raymond, do it properly.
甲が乙を隠す
A hides B,
そんじょ隆参戦さん お疲れさん
well then, Takashi-san joins the fray, good work.
四捨五入してみな
Try rounding it off,
死者五人どこ行った？
where did the five victims go?
謎解きはまだまだ
The mystery-solving is far from over.
「そして誰もいなくなったわ」
"And then there were none."
およしになって おやめになって 怪事件
Please stop, please cease, this strange case.
お下げ揺らす 探偵さん
Swinging her pigtails, the detective-san.
探偵さん！
Detective-san!
ノックスべべ ガストンべべ いかないで、ああもう
Knox baby, Gaston baby, don't go, ah geez...
先生の意地悪は毎度
Sensei's meanness is a constant.
ドトハライ・ドットコム あちゃちゃちゃパリパリ
Dotobarai dot com, achachacha pari-pari,
エブリバディわんこそば
Everybody, Wanko Soba.
「たまには自分で考えたまえ」
"Try thinking for yourself once in a while."
ドトハライ・ドットコム あちゃちゃちゃドンシャリ
Dotobarai dot com, achachacha don-shari.
エブリバディ
Everybody
アリバイ
Alibi
ナイ ナイ ナイ ナイ
None, none, none, none
怪盗の目の 穴にはまり
Falling into the trap of the phantom thief's eyes,
次々と 姿を消していく
one after another they disappear,
名探偵たち
the great detectives.
そして 探偵の居ぬ間に
And while the detective is away,
人々の心は 密室となった
people's hearts became locked rooms.
「でも、それならどうしてあたしだけが無事だったんでしょうか？」
"But then why was I the only one who was safe?"
「その答えはひとつしか考えられない」
"There can only be one answer to that."
「と、云うと……？」
"Which is...?"
「あまりに無能すぎるが故に、」
"Because you are too incompetent,"
「きみは探偵として勘定にも入れられていなかったのだ!」
"you weren't even counted as a detective!"
「いーやー!」
"Nooo!"
およしになって おやめになって 怪奇事件
Please stop, please quit this mysterious case.
おさげ揺らす 探偵さん
The detective shaking her pigtails,
『探偵さん!』
"Detective!"
Knock's baby, Got it's baby, 行かないで
Knock's baby, Got it's baby, don't go.
a-m-o-r 先生の 意地悪イケズ
A-M-O-R, Professor's mean trick.
ロードショートリック ハットトリック
Roadshow trick, hat trick,
難事件
it's a difficult case.
推理作家の先生
The mystery writer professor.
うだらうだら 言わないで
Don't just mumble on and on.
あぁもう 頭がこんがらがってきたけど
Ah, my head is getting all tangled up, but...
来いよ来いよ トリック
Come on, come on, trick,
甘い接待
sweet entertainment.
通りゃんせ
Toryanse.
小さい2人の子供が約束した、
Two small children made a promise,
ずっといっしょに笑っていようの約束。
a promise to always laugh together.
今もなお、2人の絆は確かなもので
Even now, the bond between the two is certain,
友情と愛情が織りなす素敵な物語。
a wonderful story woven with friendship and love.
「あははっ…なんでもないことに、妙にツボっちゃう時あるよねっ」
"Ahaha... there are times when you just strangely crack up at nothing, right?"
あぁ 恋に落ち たまゆら 開花 止まらないや
Ah, the fleeting moment I fell in love, the blooming won't stop.
何度も捲って 心をかし
Flipping through it again and again, the heart is interesting.
泣いてばっかだったの それがどうだ今や
I was always crying, but what about now?
腹捩るくらい笑う
I laugh until my sides hurt.
ずっと一緒に笑って 心をかし
Always laughing together, the heart is interesting.
ずっと一緒に笑う
Always laughing together.
最後の日を笑う
Laughing on the last day.
きみが持ってる 白い花に
In the white flower you hold,
あたし見合わない 悲しくなる
I don't fit, it makes me sad.
無垢な恋とか 正しさとか
Innocent love or righteousness,
誰も教えてくれなかった
no one taught me either.
昨日会ったばっかで 今日またどっか会えたら
I met you just yesterday, if I could meet you somewhere today,
なんて思う暮らし 慎ましいくらいよね
what a way to live, thinking that. It's quite humble, isn't it?
全部許されたの
Everything was forgiven.
びっくりしちゃってさ
I was surprised,
涙あふれてたよ
tears were overflowing.
もう愛になる花歌 透き通った空
The flower song that is now love, the clear sky.
手をつないでた 夢のしるし
Hand in hand, a sign of a dream.
どんな前世だってさ
Whatever the past life was,
忘れたっていいんだ
it's okay if I forgot it.
きみと笑えるなら
If I can laugh with you.
心が触れるたび 綺麗な音鳴る
Every time our hearts touch, a beautiful sound rings.
目と目が合って くすぐったいね
When our eyes meet, it tickles, doesn't it?
なんでもないこと 妙にツボるね
I'm strangely drawn to trivial things.
全部教えてくれて
Everything you taught me,
ありがとう
thank you.
きみが持ってる 白い花を
The white flower you hold,
あたしの紅色と 合わせたら
if I combine it with my crimson color,
霜が解けては 雲が行く
the frost melts and the clouds go.
もう寒くないよ
It's not cold anymore.
あぁ 恋に落ち たまゆら 開花 止まらないや
Ah, the fleeting moment I fell in love, the blooming won't stop.
何度も捲って 心をかし
Flipping through it again and again, the heart is interesting.
泣いてばっかだったの それがどうだ今や
I was always crying, but what about now?
腹捩るくらい笑う
I laugh until my sides hurt.
ずっと一緒に笑って
Always laughing together.
恋に落ちたまゆら
In that fleeting moment I fell in love...
心をかし
the heart is interesting.
愛になる花歌
The flower song that becomes love.
ずっと一緒に笑う
Always laughing together.
最後の日を笑う
Laughing on the last day.
これは、遠い遠い 名も知らぬ世界で、
This is, in a far, far away world with no name...
死の呪いがかけられた 少女のお話
This is the tale of a girl cursed with death.
遠い遠い時の果て そこに住まう人は皆
At the far ends of time, where everyone who lives there...
永遠の命をもつ 世界での話
has eternal life; this is a tale from that world.
赤い実の成る木の下 La La Lu La 生まれながらに
Under a tree bearing red fruit, La La Lu La, born with it,
死の呪いがかけられた 少女の話
the tale of a girl cursed with death.
色付いた街外れ 蒼く光る湖畔
At the edge of a colored town, by a blue-shining lake,
赤い実のお菓子屋
is a shop of red fruit sweets.
ちょっぴり寒くなった今日は 妙に誇らしげ
Today, a bit colder than usual, looking strangely proud,
自信作を 売りに行く
she goes to sell her pride and joy.
待ってて 今度こそ 美味しいんだから
Wait for me, this time it's delicious!
時計塔の見える市 行き交う人 珍しく顔 華やがね
In the city of the clock tower, people's faces are unusually bright.
La La Lu La Lucky!!
物憂げな街の隅 ひとり
Alone in a corner of the listless town,
赤い実のパイどうですか
How about a red fruit pie?
自信作なの
It's my pride and joy.
そんなのひとつも売れないさ 少女を見て蔑む人達
No one will buy such a thing, the people look with contempt.
みんなと何も変わらないのに 美味しくできたのに
Even though I'm no different, even though I made it delicious,
今日も声は届かないので
my voice doesn't reach them today either.
まるで透明になったみたいだわ
It's like I've become transparent.
そして誰もが知らぬふりをした
And everyone pretended not to know,
何故なら少女は呪われているから
because the girl is cursed.
死んだ世界でただひとり 生きていた少女の話
In a dead world, just one girl was alive; this is that tale.
夜なべでアレンジバイト にっこりスマイル引下げ
Working all night on an arrangement, with a smile pulled down,
少女はまた諦めない
the girl won't give up.
時計塔の針も空を指して お腹も鳴るそんな時
The clock tower points to the sky, and my stomach growls, then...
ふと後ろから人が少女を押す
someone suddenly pushes the girl from behind.
甘い籠は落ちる
The basket of sweets falls.
お菓子をふみ行く人達 平気な顔してさ 惨めに拾い集める
Indifferent people trample the sweets. Gathering them up miserably,
ふともうひとりの手が どろどろのパイを
suddenly another hand takes a muddy pie...
もろに口に入れて「おいしいね」
and puts it in their mouth, saying, 'It's delicious.'
その声で心は溢れた
With that voice, my heart overflowed.
まるで輪郭を描いたみたいだわ
It's like they drew my outline.
そして彼は手を差し出した
And he held out his hand,
何故なら少女に呪われているから
because he is cursed by the girl.
死んだ世界でただふたり 生きていた遠い物語
In a dead world, just the two of us were alive; a distant story.
街の人達は哀れむ 赤い実を食べて呪われた者を
The townspeople pity those cursed by eating the red fruit.
永遠に切られずに死ぬのさ
'To die without being cut forever,'
なんて可哀想な話
what a pitiful tale.
ふたりは笑う それでも笑う
They both laugh, they still laugh.
La La La とっても素敵な呪いね
La La La, what a wonderful curse.
たとえ明日死んでも 今が確かに大切になるから
Even if we die tomorrow, because now is truly precious.
もう声は届かないので
My voice won't reach them anymore,
まるで透明になったみたいだわ
it's like I've become transparent.
そして誰もが知らぬふりをした
And everyone pretended not to know,
何故なら世界が呪われているから
because the world is cursed.
永遠の呪いは解かれていた
The eternal curse was broken.
まるでふたりの方が狂ったみたいだろう
It looks as if the two of them were the ones who went mad.
そして、いつか
And then, one day,
笑うように眠る
I'll sleep as if smiling.
なぜならサヨナラは
Because goodbyes...
赦されているから
...are forgiven.
死んだ世界でただ二人だけが
In this dying world, we two alone...
幸せだった
Were happy.
さて、今日はこれくらいにしておきましょう。
Well, let's call it a day for now.
...そろそろ時間になりましたし
...It's about time, anyway.
...え？どこへ向かうのかって？
...Eh? Where am I going?
今日は何の日かご存知ないのですか？
Do you not know what today is?
今日は、この王国の地下深くにある冥界でのハロウィンパーティーですよ！
Today is the Halloween party in the underworld, deep beneath this kingdom!
死者と生者が楽しむ年に一度のお祭りです。
It's a once-a-year festival where the dead and the living enjoy themselves together.
さあ、一緒に向かいましょう。
Come, let's head there together.
でも、気をつけて。パーティーとは言え、死者が住まう冥界です。
But be careful. Even if it's a party, it's the underworld where the dead reside.
誰かの思念や死者たちによって奇妙な事が起こるかもしれません。
Strange things may happen due to someone's thoughts or the dead themselves.
でも、決してそちらに耳を傾けすぎてはいけませんよ...
But, you must never listen too closely to them...
それでは、参りましょう。
Now then, let's go.
誰かが言いました
Someone said,
激しく燃えるものほど
The more intensely something burns,
煌めく引き換えに
in exchange for its sparkle,
その身をすぐ焦がしきると
it instantly burns its own body away.
数ある燭台に
In the many candlesticks,
お好きな火を灯しましょう
let's light the fire of your choice.
期待と裏腹に
In contrast to expectations,
燻ればおぞましい憎さ
if it smolders, it becomes a gruesome hatred.
ランランランラン
La la la la
右手には錆びた時計
In the right hand, a rusted clock,
ランランランラン
La la la la
左には油の筒
In the left, a cylinder of oil.
ランランランラン
La la la la
錆のドレスを着飾って　さあ
Dress up in a dress of rust, and now...
激しく　儚く
Intensely, transiently,
青く燃える花びら
the blue burning petals
瞬きゆらめく
twinkle and flicker.
生を彩り照らせ
Light up and color life,
いずれ尽き果てる未来へと
towards a future that will eventually run out.
ゆりかごの目の前で
In front of the cradle,
あまねく飛び交う銃弾
bullets flying all around.
指だけ動かせば
If you just move your finger,
容易くその火は潰える
that fire is easily extinguished.
仮初の情熱で
With a fleeting passion,
焼け爛れた舌では
with a scorched tongue,
上手に喋ることができないようで
it seems you cannot speak well.
喉元すぎても
Even if it passes the throat,
毒を孕ませて
let it be filled with poison,
やがては筋を腐らせる
and eventually, it will rot the very core.
やがては肺を腐らせるでしょう
Eventually, it will rot your lungs
揺らぐ死と生の間
Swaying between life and death
耽ける心と歌う
Singing with a heart that indulges
描いた最愛の終幕を
The most beloved finale I drew
激しく 儚く
Intense, fleeting,
青く燃ゆる花びら
blue burning petals
瞬き ゆらめく
Twinkling, flickering,
生を彩り照らせ
color and illuminate life
いずれ尽き果てるその先へ
To what lies beyond the eventual end
あちらの世界に引きずり込まれないうちに
Before we get dragged into that world,
早く会場へ向かわないといけませんね。
we must head to the venue quickly.
気を付けてついてきてくださいね。
Please follow closely and be careful.
あまり深入りすると、おっと…
If you go too deep, oops...
そうそう、知らないほうがきっと懸命ですよ。
That's right, it's probably better not to know.
なんだかすっごく心地が良いよね。
Somehow it feels really good, doesn't it?
気づけば見知らぬ世界に立っていた
Before I knew it, I was standing in an unfamiliar world.
何処かも分からず
Not knowing where I was,
毎日毎日毎日泣いていた
I cried every single day.
なんて暇もなく Happy Time!
No time for that, Happy Time!
おかしな面々が Happy Time!
Strange people, Happy Time!
おどけて転がるの
Rolling around playfully
その馬鹿馬鹿しさに希望も恐怖もなくなった
In that foolishness, hope and fear disappeared.
確かそうアタシには為すべき仕事
For sure, I have a job to do
愛の楼閣
Love's pavilion
パンプキン、ヘッドギア
Pumpkin, headset
だけどなんかどーでもいい
But somehow it doesn't matter.
さぁ始まった夢の夜だ
So the dream night has begun
音楽が響いて鳴り止まない
The music is echoing and it won't stop
声を揃えて叫べ今日は
Ready your voices and shout today is...
アメイジングハッピーハロウィンナイト
Amazing Happy Halloween Night!
ジャック、いたずら、無礼講だ
Jack, mischief, it's a free-for-all
真面目に生きてても割に合わない
Living seriously isn't worth it
なんでもありさ何故って今日は
Anything goes because today is...
アメイジングハッピーハロウィンナイト
Amazing Happy Halloween Night!
消えちゃった！
It disappeared!
とはないなんてそう永遠に
There's no such thing, yes, forever
消えちゃった！
It disappeared!
思想、ルール、倫理、関係ない
Ideology, rules, ethics, it doesn't matter
アメイジングハッピーハロウィンナイト
Amazing Happy Halloween Night!
「私はロボットではありません」に
To "I am not a robot"
無心でチェックし解答するけれど
I check and answer absentmindedly, but
ほんとうにそうかな
Is that really so?
Happy Life!
取り戻せ音に乗せて
Get it back on the sound
デタラメに踊るの
Dancing randomly
その繰り返しのなか懐疑心も失った
In that repetition, I lost even my doubt.
意思のない様まるで
Like a person without a will
ロボットーした電気羊
A robot-like electric sheep
ナイトメア、NPC
Nightmare, NPC
だけどなんか心地がいい
But somehow it feels good.
What?
おっと音声が乱れました
Oops, the audio got messy
お気になさらずに皆々様
Please don't mind it, everyone
そんなお口は縫い合わせて
Let's sew those mouths shut
アメイジングハッピーハロウィンナイト
Amazing Happy Halloween Night!
良い子の口にはチョコとキャンディ
Chocolate and candy for good children's mouths
歯に絹着せってちゃ噛み合わない
Mincing words won't work here
気をとり直し皆なでどうぞ
Pull yourselves together, everyone please
アメイジングハッピーハロウィンナイト
Amazing Happy Halloween Night!
知っちゃった！知っちゃった！
I found out! I found out!
全部全部理解した
I understood everything, everything
だから何も見たくねえわ
So I don't want to see anything
さぁ始まった夢の夜だ
So the dream night has begun
音楽が響いて鳴り止まない
The music is echoing and it won't stop
声を揃えて叫べ今日は
Ready your voices and shout today is...
アメイジングハッピーハロウィンナイト
Amazing Happy Halloween Night!
ジャック、いたずら、無礼講だ
Jack, mischief, it's a free-for-all
真面目に生きてても割に合わない
Living seriously isn't worth it
なんでもありさ何故って今日は
Anything goes because today is...
アメイジングハッピーハロウィンナイト
Amazing Happy Halloween Night!
泣いちゃった！
I cried!
知らない方がきっと懸命ね
It's probably better not to know
泣いちゃった！
I cried!
このパーティーに終わりはない
This party has no end
アメイジングハッピーハロウィンナイト
Amazing Happy Halloween Night!
Amazing Happy Halloween Night
トリック・オア・トリート！
Trick or Treat!
お菓子をくれても
Even if you give me sweets,
イタズラはしちゃうよ！
I'll play a prank!
ようこそ everyone
Welcome everyone,
身の毛もよだつこの spooky night
to this hair-raising spooky night!
ハラの底まで揺れ
Shake to the bottom of your stomach,
左 kick & bass & hats & trumpet
Left kick & bass & hats & trumpet!
ランタンと swingin' beat
Lantern and swingin' beat,
赤い靴で踊り狂えば
if you dance wildly in red shoes,
浮世の憂いも
even the worries of this world
忘れられるでしょ
will be forgotten, right?
巷も街中じゃ お化けよりも怖い人たち
In the streets and all over town, people scarier than ghosts
増えすぎちゃってすぐに
have increased so much that immediately it's
1 out, 2 out, 3 out, knockout!!
コンプライアンスも
Even in this world
厳しめの世の中ですが
where compliance is strict,
恐怖のリライト 請け負います
we'll take on the rewrite of fear.
Give me a cherry pie,
それとも may I choke you up?
or may I choke you up?
Give me a flowy dress,
それとも may I stab you to death?
or may I stab you to death?
Poison, rope, or cake?
Knife, scissors, raspberry flake?
Choose one...
Choose one!
「さぁ 選んで」
"Now, choose."
なんちゃって ドッキリ大成功
Just kidding! The prank was a huge success!
響くパンパカパンパカファンファーレで
With the echoing fanfare,
にっこり笑っちゃってはいピース
smile and say "peace!"
あー怖かったななんて
Saying "Oh, that was scary,"
座り込んで涙目で
sitting down with teary eyes,
笑う顔見たいな
I want to see your laughing face.
ちっぽけな箱の中の
If you're going to be frightened
モンスターに怯えるくらいなら
by monsters in a tiny box,
いつだってここにおいで
come here anytime!
もっとずっと本能的で楽しくなれる
You can be much more instinctive and have fun.
恐怖と踊っちゃおうぜ
Let's dance with fear!
三相三身でキマッてカタルシス
Three phases, three bodies, settling in catharsis.
もういっちょ感情ジェットコースターで
One more time on the emotional roller coaster,
ゴキゲンデトックス
cheerful detox!
Uh-oh!
満月が暴く醜悪な本性
The full moon reveals an ugly true nature.
デタラメに杖振り回し hocus pocus
Waving a staff randomly, hocus pocus.
劣等感を苗床に育つ呪いを
A curse growing in the seedbed of inferiority complexes,
摘み取る術を知ってるかい？
do you know the way to pluck it out?
「迷える哀れな子羊たちよ」
"O wandering, pitiful little lambs."
「お菓子が欲しいかい？」
"Do you want sweets?"
「それとも安らぎが欲しいかい？」
"Or do you want peace?"
「永遠に求め続けるの？」
"Will you keep seeking forever?"
「それならば、ずっと苦しいままだ」
"If so, you will remain in pain forever."
「恐怖からの解放によって」
"By liberation from fear,"
「成し得る救済があるのならば」
"if there is a salvation that can be achieved,"
「この目隠しはそのままで」
"leave this blindfold as it is."
「さぁ、」
"Now,"
「イタズラ完了」
"prank completed."
永遠に断ち切れない 呪いの鎖に囚われ
Trapped in the chains of a curse that can never be severed,
朽ち果ててしまう前に
before it rots away...
脳みそちょっと弄るだけで あら不思議
Just a little tinkering with the brain, and oh, how strange!
こんなに気持ち良くて 気分爽快
It feels so good, so refreshing!
なんちゃって ドッキリ大成功
Just kidding! The prank was a huge success!
響くパンパカパンパカファンファーレで
With the echoing fanfare,
にっこり笑っちゃってはいポーズ
smile and strike a pose!
あー辛かったななんて
Saying "Oh, that was painful,"
へたり込んで涙目で
collapsing with teary eyes,
笑う顔っていいな
a laughing face is nice.
もう苦しまなくていいよ
You don't have to suffer anymore,
こんなに頑張ったんだから
you've worked so hard.
躊躇わずこっちにおいで
Come here without hesitation!
もうずっと本能的に気持ち良いだけの
To a place that just feels good instinctively,
ゴールを見せてあげる
I'll show you the goal.
困窮 窮まってこそ光るカタルシス
Catharsis that shines only when distress is at its limit.
もういっちょ 因果全リセットで
One more time, resetting all karma,
魂デトックス
soul detox!
Uh-oh!
いつかの、あったかもしれない世界の出来事までをも
Even the events of an unknown world that might have once existed,
この冥界ではこうして思念として漂っているんだね
in this underworld, they float like this as thoughts.
あまり深入りしてはいけないよ、こういうのが一番たちが悪い
You shouldn't get too deeply involved; these kinds are the most troublesome.
私はただ、あなたを愛していただけ
I just loved you.
物言わぬ唇に生気を吹き込んで、
Blowing life into the lips that don't speak,
今宵「あなた」は甦る
tonight, you will awaken
あの頃の姿で。
in the appearance of those days.
ネクロの花嫁
The Bride of Necro
白肌の娘が咳をした。
The pale-skinned girl coughed.
「この身体貴方に捧げるわ」
“I will offer this body to you.”
白服の医者が囁いた。
The white-clad doctor whispered.
「迎えに行くよ」
“I’m coming to pick you up.”
白肌の娘は朽ち果てた。
The pale-skinned girl withered away.
世界の誰にも見棄てられ。
Forsaken by everyone in the world.
白服の医者は憐れんで、
The white-clad doctor took pity on her,
誰も知らない居場所で眠らせた。
and let her sleep in a place no one knows.
朽ちてもまだ美しい顔で、
With her withered, yet still beautiful face,
ふたりしかいない霊廟で、
in the mausoleum where only the two of them are,
医者は恋をした。
the doctor fell in love.
それは永遠の恋か。禁断の行為か。
Was it eternal love? A forbidden act?
また逢いたいと願うだけ。
Only wishing to meet again.
それが罪なのでしょうか。
Is that a sin?
物謂わぬ口唇に生気を吹き込んで、
Breathing life into the silent lips,
今宵ふたりは結ばれる。祝福もされずに。
tonight the two are bound together. Without even a blessing.
物謂わぬ口唇に生気を吹き込んで、
Breathing life into the silent lips,
「傷ついた眼窩に青いガラスを」
“Blue glass for the wounded eye sockets.”
「破れかけた腕に絹の布を」
“Silk cloth for the torn arms.”
「侵された内臓に綿のガーゼを」
“Cotton gauze for the affected internal organs.”
「宝石で飾った白いドレスを」
“A white dress adorned with jewels.”
朽ちゆくたび
Every time they wither,
取り繕って、
mending and patching,
恋を謳って、また医者は
singing of love, the doctor again
手を染め続けた。
continued to stain his hands.
やがて暴かれたのは醜い怪物で、
Eventually, what was revealed was a hideous monster,
それを造り上げた医者は弁駁を叫んだ。
and the doctor who created it, shouted his justification.
「これは永遠の恋だ。彼女の願望だ。」
“This is an eternal love. It's her desire.”
「死にゆくと決めたお前らが見棄てた女じゃないか。」
“Isn't she the woman you all abandoned, deciding she was to die?”
嗚呼…哀しき花嫁。物謂えぬままで、
Ah... poor bride, left unable to speak,
今宵ふたりは裁かれる。
tonight the two are judged.
彼女を見棄てた人達の正義で。
By the justice of the people who abandoned her.
正しいのはだあれ？
Who is the one who's right?
さて、ハロウィンパーティーもついにフィナーレ。
Well, the Halloween party is finally at its finale.
ここで、ご参加くださった国民の皆様へ、冥界からのお土産品のご紹介です。
And now, to all the citizens who participated, here is an introduction to the souvenirs from the underworld.
お土産品は、全4種類。
There are a total of four types of souvenirs.
フルセットでご購入いただいた皆様には、特典もございます。
For those who purchase the full set, there is also a special bonus.
ご一緒に詳しく見ていきましょう。
Let's take a closer look together.
まず1つ目。
First, the first one.
今回の冥界ハロウィンナイトをイメージした、ワイドラバーマットです。
A wide rubber mat inspired by this underworld Halloween night.
国王様の横には、冥界の女王の姿が。
Next to the King is the figure of the Queen of the Underworld.
名を、ナイラというそうです。
Her name is said to be Naira.
冥界のハロウィンを存分に楽しんでほしいという気持ちを込めた、
Filled with the desire for you to fully enjoy the underworld Halloween,
彼女のイメージソングも、この後お披露目予定なので、お楽しみに。
her image song is also scheduled to be unveiled later, so please look forward to it.
素敵なイラストは、Matcha様に描いていただきました。
The wonderful illustration was drawn by Matcha-sama.
2つ目は、パスポート風FBKINGDOMシール帳です。
The second one is a passport-style FBKINGDOM Sticker Book.
このシール帳には、これからたくさんの思い出を記していきたいですね。
I want to record many memories in this sticker book from now on.
王国の軌跡として、国民の皆様も今後集めてみてはいかがでしょうか。
As a trail of the kingdom, why don't you all, the citizens, try collecting them in the future?
その1歩として、今回のキービジュアルのステッカーを、1枚、封入しております。
As the first step, one sticker of this key visual is enclosed.
3つ目は、SUKONBU FACTORYより、キングフブちゃんのぬいぐるみです。
The third one is the King Fubu-chan plushie from SUKONBU FACTORY.
こちらは国王自らデザインをしており、とても愛らしいぬいぐるみとなっております。
This one was designed by the King himself, and it's a very adorable plushie.
前回のボリューム1のぬいぐるみをお持ちの方は、ご一緒にかざってあげてくださいね。
If you have the plushie from the previous Volume 1, please display them together.
4つ目は、王国リボンチャームです。
The fourth one is the Kingdom Ribbon Charm.
こちらは、司書である私の胸元のリボンが再現されております。
This reproduces the ribbon on the chest of me, the librarian.
カバンにつけたり...
Attach it to your bag...
カバンにつけるもよし
You can attach it to your bag,
ペンライトにつけるもよしと
or even to your penlight.
多機能なリボンチャームとなっておりますので
Since it's a multi-functional ribbon charm,
皆様の推し活とやらに是非ご活用ください
please use it for your fan activities!
最後は特典のおしらせです
Finally, here is an announcement about the bonuses.
フルセットご購入の方全員に
To everyone who purchases the full set,
チェキ風ブロマイドカードを１つお付けいたします
we'll include one cheki-style bromide card.
複製サインと国王からのメッセージもあるそうですよ
It also has a printed signature and a message from the King!
数量限定版は直筆サイン入りですので
The limited edition version is hand-signed,
皆様お早めに
so everyone, be quick!
以上、今回のお土産品紹介でした
That's all for the merchandise introduction.
さて、このあとは冥界の女王様をイメージした楽曲
Now, next is a song inspired by the Queen of the Underworld,
冥界Halloween Night!のお披露目です
the debut of 'Underworld Halloween Night!'
楽しんだ後は無事王国へお帰りくださいね
After enjoying it, please return safely to the Kingdom.
それでは
Well then...
Welcome！さあ、踊ろうよ
Welcome! Now, let's dance,
This is Halloween Night！
This is Halloween Night!
冥界を挙げてのParty (Party)
Party in the underworld (Party)
ルール違反はダメですWarning (Warning)
Rule violations are not allowed, Warning (Warning)
説明は一度きり (きり)
The explanation is only once (once)
聞き逃せばあの世行き！
If you miss it, you're going to the other world!
冗談です
Just kidding
(いち) お菓子を持って
(One) Bring snacks
(に) 仮装して盛って
(Two) Dress up and show off
(さん) 生者か死者かは隠す事
(Three) Hide whether you're living or dead
それと…
And...
(よん！) いつだって笑顔で
(Four!) Always with a smile
(ご！)
(Five!)
油断気満々で
With a free and easy attitude
最後の最後はご無事で帰る事
In the very end, return safely
一人きりじゃつまらないわ
It's no fun being all alone
この退屈な王城の玉座で
On the throne of this boring royal castle
幾許（いくばく）ずっと待ちわびてた
I've been waiting for ages
人恋しいとか？
Wait, are you lovesick?
ヤダ！そんなんじゃないってば！
No way! That's not it at all!
『Let's冥界Halloween Night！』
"Let's Underworld Halloween Night!"
Dancing！Dancing！闇夜にハッピーなメロデイー
Dancing! Dancing! A happy melody in the dark night
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 冥界Halloween Night！
Ra-ta-ta, Ra-ta-ta, Underworld Halloween Night!
Swinging！Swinging！ゾッとして愉快なアイロニー
Swinging! Swinging! A thrilling, pleasant irony
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 狂宴のショータイム！
Ra-ta-ta, Ra-ta-ta, The banquet's showtime!
(Pa Pa Pa) 恐ろしや
(Pa Pa Pa) How scary
(Pa Pa Pa) うらめしや
(Pa Pa Pa) I'm jealous
皆 皆 我さえも忘れてる
Everyone, everyone, even I've forgotten
あらら？ (Pa Pa Pa) 美味しそうな
Oh? (Pa Pa Pa) How delicious
(Pa Pa Pa) 魂だわ！
(Pa Pa Pa) It's your soul!
Welcome！さあ、踊ろうよ
Welcome! Now, let's dance,
This is Halloween Night！
This is Halloween Night!
響く雅なTuning (Tuning)
Resonating, elegant Tuning (Tuning)
その不協和音さえもMusic (Music)
Even that dissonance is Music (Music)
王室のドアが開き (開き)
The royal doors open (open)
拍手喝采が起こる
Thunderous applause ensues
快感です♡
It feels so good♡
(いち) ロウソクを持って
(One) Bring candles
(に) ドレス纏って
(Two) Dress up in a gown
(さん) 女王の私のお出ましです！
(Three) Here I am, the Queen!
(よん！) 手を取り合って
(Four!) Take my hand
(ご！) 今日は無礼講で
(Five!) Today, let's let loose
私に見せられちゃったら最後です♡
Once you've shown me, it's the end♡
鮮やかなステップ くるり舞ってワルツ
Vibrant steps, twirling in a waltz
悪戯なこのリズムに揺られて
Swaying to this mischievous rhythm
この楽しさ 癖になるわ
This fun will become a habit
時間切れとか…
Running out of time?
ヤダ！全然足りないってば！
No way! It's not nearly enough!
『Let's冥界Halloween Night！』
"Let's Underworld Halloween Night!"
Dancing！Dancing！一夜の奇怪なメモリー
Dancing! Dancing! A strange memory for one night
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 冥界Halloween Night！
Ra-ta-ta, Ra-ta-ta, Underworld Halloween Night!
Sweety！Sweety！おもむろに頬張るキャンディー
Sweety! Sweety! Slowly stuffing candies in our cheeks
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ ああ、もっと頂戴！
Ra-ta-ta, Ra-ta-ta, Ah, give me more!
うたかたの夢 淡い霧の中溶けて
A transient dream melts away in the pale mist
青白い頬を 涙が伝った
Tears streamed down pale cheeks
この歌は誰の為？自問自答の末
Who is this song for? After some soul-searching...
無垢の箱を開けたら
If you open the pure box
時を戻す魔法使っちゃおうかな？
Maybe I should use magic to turn back time?
Dancing！Dancing！闇夜にハッピーなメロデイー
Dancing! Dancing! A happy melody in the dark night
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 冥界Halloween Night！
Ra-ta-ta, Ra-ta-ta, Underworld Halloween Night!
Swinging！Swinging！ゾッとして愉快なアイロニー
Swinging! Swinging! A thrilling, pleasant irony
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 狂宴のショータイム！
Ra-ta-ta, Ra-ta-ta, The banquet's showtime!
(Pa Pa Pa) 恐ろしや
(Pa Pa Pa) How scary
(Pa Pa Pa) うらめしや
(Pa Pa Pa) I'm jealous
皆 皆 我さえも忘れてる
Everyone, everyone, even I've forgotten
あらら？ (Pa Pa Pa) 美味しそうな
Oh? (Pa Pa Pa) How delicious
(Pa Pa Pa) 魂だわ！
(Pa Pa Pa) It's your soul!
Welcome！さあ、踊ろうよ
Welcome! Now, let's dance,
This is Halloween Night！
This is Halloween Night!
ハロウィンパーティー、いかがでしたでしょうか？
How was the Halloween party?
ちゃんとこちら側の王国に戻ってこられていますか？
Were you able to return to this side's kingdom?
冥界の女王様に気に入られてしまうと
If the Queen of the Underworld takes a liking to you,
魂を奪われてしまって、帰ってこられませんからね。
she might steal your soul, and you won't return.
戻ってこられてラッキーでした。
You were lucky to be able to return.
なんて。
Just kidding.
あ、今日のお話はどうでしたか？
Oh, how was today's story?
楽しかったでしょうか？
Did you enjoy it?
私が特にお気に入りは、探偵のお話でして。
My particular favorite was the detective story.
今回お聞かせできて、とっても嬉しかったです。
I was very happy to be able to tell it to you.
そうだ。いつかあなたのお話も聞かせてくださいね。
That's right. Please tell me your story someday.
もしかすると、あの本に、
Perhaps, in that book...
あなたのお話も書き記されるかもしれませんよ。
...your story will be recorded as well.
なんといっても、摩訶不思議な本ですから。
After all, it's a mysterious book.
何が起こるか、司書である私にもわかりません。
Even I, the librarian, don't know what will happen.
さて、そろそろお時間ですね。
Well, it's about time.
またお話が聞きたくなりましたら、
If you ever want to hear a story again,
いつでもこの王国図書館へお越しください。
please come to this Kingdom Library anytime.
それでは、さようなら。
Well then, goodbye.
ハジマリはきっとひとつの願い
The beginning is surely a single wish,
それを抱いて私たちは
embracing that, we are...
生まれた孤独な夜空
Born into the lonely night sky,
震える指で点と点を繋げよう
let's connect the dots with trembling fingers.
LIVE Blu-ray 発売決定！
LIVE Blu-ray Release Decided!
すこん部の皆さん、準備はできてますか？
Sukonbu fans, are you ready?
Say! Fanfare! いきましょう！
Say! Fanfare! Let's go!
Say! ほら、その顔上げて みんなで手を取れば
Say! Look, lift your face; if we all hold hands,
Say! まだまだ道中 世界を越えよ
Say! We're still in the middle of the road.
Say! ほら、推し推し固まり
Say! Look, the support is piling up;
止まらない専欲ですから！
because it's a desire that won't stop!
夢を書きかえたら 追いかけ続けよう
If we rewrite our dreams, let's keep chasing them.
ともに 繋ぐ ファンファーレ Go!
Together, connecting, fanfare Go!
宝物いくつか自分自身の
With some treasures of my own...
輝きを見失ったときには
When I lost sight of my own brilliance,
思い出してね僕らの星座は
remember, our constellation...
君がいるから輝く
shines because you are here.
Oh Yeah! 無数の星の中
Oh Yeah! Among countless stars,
Oh Yeah! 光を君がくれた
Oh Yeah! You gave me the light.
もっと越えていけるさ
We can go even further.
スパノバ起こせ今
Set off a supernova now.
何度だって飛べる
We can fly any number of times.
これは紛れもなく僕らの奇跡
This is undoubtedly our miracle.
Hi Friends!
ベストウィッシュ！すこん部ー！
Best wishes! Sukonbu!
Blu-ray 発売決定！！
Blu-ray Release Decided!!